{
"QnAs":[
  {
    "Question": "What is SAT?",
    "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method based on creating an affectional bond with our child for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion cheerfulness and creativity) re-processing negative experiences and developing positive cognitive behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems and exercises to reduce negative affects and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many protocols?",
    "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course which is two weeks."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What goal should I have?",
    "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides us towards growth and self-development in society; e.g. success in an academic scientific literary philosophical athletic spiritual professional charitable manufacturing or commercial field.\nIf we don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, we try to find it as we practice the protocols."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
    "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self simply called adult into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self simply called our child in these notes:\n1- Introduction to attachment theory and SAT\n2- Connection with the child\n3- Falling in love with the child\n4- Developmental training for the child"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why do I need role-play?",
    "Answer": "Our problems to properly manage our emotions is usually rooted in our childhood development.\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child and through role-playing, they become a parent for their child.\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a grand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potentials and higher goals."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why can’t I feel the improvement?",
    "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols.\nNon-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood and then consolidated by repetition in later years.\nCreation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
  },
 {
  "Question": "What is attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory is a psychological, evolutionary, and ethological theory concerning relationships between humans. The most important tenet is that young children need to develop a relationship with at least one primary caregiver for normal social and emotional development. The theory was formulated by psychiatrist and psychoanalyst John Bowlby."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is attachment?",
  "Answer": "Within attachment theory, the attachment means an affectional bond or tie between an individual and an attachment figure (usually a caregiver). Such bonds may be reciprocal between two adults, but between a child and a caregiver, these bonds are based on the child's need for safety, security, and protection — which is most important in infancy and childhood. In child-to-adult relationships, the child's tie is called the \"attachment\" and the caregiver's reciprocal equivalent is referred to as the \"care-giving bond\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Does attachment behaviour indicate security?",
  "Answer": "The strength of a child's attachment behaviour in a given circumstance does not indicate the 'strength' of the attachment bond. Some insecure children will routinely display very pronounced attachment behaviours, while many secure children find that there is no great need to engage in either intense or frequent shows of attachment behaviour."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How does attachment change from childhood to adolescence?",
  "Answer": "Childhood and adolescence allow the development of an internal working model useful for forming attachments. This internal working model is related to the individual's state of mind which develops with respect to attachment generally and explores how attachment functions in relationship dynamics based on childhood and adolescent experience. The organization of an internal working model is generally seen as leading to more stable attachments in those who develop such a model, rather than those who rely more on the individual's state of mind alone in forming new attachments.\\n\\nAge, cognitive growth, and continued social experience advance the development and complexity of the internal working model. Attachment-related behaviours lose some characteristics typical of the infant-toddler period and take on age-related tendencies. The preschool period involves the use of negotiation and bargaining. For example, four-year-olds are not distressed by separation if they and their caregiver have already negotiated a shared plan for the separation and reunion.\\n\\nIdeally, these social skills become incorporated into the internal working model to be used with other children and later with adult peers. As children move into the school years at about six years old, most develop a goal-corrected partnership with parents, in which each partner is willing to compromise in order to maintain a gratifying relationship. By middle childhood, the goal of the attachment behavioural system has changed from proximity to the attachment figure to availability. Generally, a child is content with longer separations, provided contact—or the possibility of physically reuniting, if needed—is available. Attachment behaviours such as clinging and following decline and self-reliance increase. By middle childhood (ages 7–11), there may be a shift toward mutual [coregulation](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Coregulation) of secure-base contact in which caregiver and child negotiate methods of maintaining communication and supervision as the child moves toward a greater degree of independence.\\n\\nThe attachment system used by adolescents is seen as a \"safety regulating system\" whose main function is to promote physical and psychological safety. There are 2 different events that can trigger the attachment system. Those triggers include the presence of potential danger or stress, internal and external, and a threat of accessibility and\/or availability of an attachment figure. The ultimate goal of the attachment system is security, so during a time of danger or inaccessibility, the behavioural system accepts felt security in the context of the availability of protection. By adolescence, we are able to find security through a variety of things, such as food, exercise, and social media. Felt security can be achieved in a number of ways, and often without the physical presence of the attachment figure. Higher levels of maturity allow adolescent teens to more capably interact with their environment on their own because the environment is perceived as less threatening. Adolescents teens will also see an increase in cognitive, emotional and behavioural maturity that dictates whether or not teens are less likely to experience conditions that activate their need for an attachment figure. For example, when teenagers get sick and stay home from school, surely they want their parents to be home so they can take care of them, but they are also able to stay home by themselves without experiencing serious amounts of distress."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attachment styles are there in adults?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory was extended to adult romantic relationships in the late 1980s by Cindy Hazan and Phillip Shaver. Four styles of attachment have been identified in adults: secure, anxious-preoccupied, dismissive-avoidant and fearful-avoidant. These roughly correspond to infant classifications: secure, insecure-ambivalent, insecure-avoidant and disorganized\/disoriented."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the biological explanations of attachment?",
  "Answer": "The quality of caregiving received in infancy and childhood directly affects an individual's neurological systems which control stress regulation. In psychophysiological research on attachment, the two main areas studied have been [autonomic responses](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Autonomic_nervous_system), such as heart rate or respiration, and the activity of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal [axis](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Hypothalamic%E2%80%93pituitary%E2%80%93adrenal_axis), a system that is responsible for the body's reaction to [stress](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Stress_(biology). Infants' physiological responses have been measured during the Strange Situation procedure looking at individual differences in infant temperament and the extent to which attachment acts as a moderator. Recent studies convey that early attachment relationships become molecularly instilled into the being, thus affecting later immune system functioning. Empirical evidence communicates that early negative experiences produce pro-inflammatory phenotype cells in the immune system, which is directly related to cardiovascular disease, autoimmune diseases, and certain types of cancer.\\n\\nRecent improvements involving methods of research have enabled researchers to further investigate the neural correlates of attachment in humans. These advances include identifying key brain structures, neural circuits, neurotransmitter systems, and neuropeptides, and how they are involved in attachment system functioning and can indicate more about a certain individual, even predict their behaviour. There is initial evidence that caregiving and attachment involve both unique and overlapping brain regions. Another issue is the role of inherited genetic factors in shaping attachments: for example, one type of [polymorphism](\/wiki\/Polymorphism_(biology) of the gene coding for the [D2](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dopamine_receptor_D2) [dopamine receptor](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dopamine_receptor) has been linked to anxious attachment and another in the gene for the [5-HT2A](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/5-HT2A_receptor) [serotonin receptor](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Serotonin_receptor) with avoidant attachment.\\n\\nStudies show that attachment in adulthood is simultaneously related to biomarkers of immunity. For example, individuals with an avoidance attachment style produce higher levels of the pro-inflammatory cytokine interleukin-6 (IL-6) when reacting to an interpersonal stressor, while individuals representing an anxious attachment style tend to have elevated cortisol production and lower numbers of T cells. Although children vary genetically and each individual requires different attachment relationships, there is consistent evidence that maternal warmth during infancy and childhood creates a safe haven for individuals resulting in superior immune system functioning. One theoretical basis for this is that it makes biological sense for children to vary in their susceptibility to rearing influence."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment theory related to crime?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory has often been applied in the discipline of [criminology](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Criminology). It has been used in an attempt to identify causal mechanisms in criminal behaviour – with uses ranging from [offender profiling](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Offender_profiling), a better understanding of types of offence and the pursuit of preventative policy. It has been found that disturbances early on in child-caregiver relationships are a risk factor for criminality. Attachment theory in this context has been described as \"perhaps the most influential of contemporary psychoanalytically oriented theories of crime\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the practical applications of attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "As a theory of [socioemotional development](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Developmental_psychology \"Developmental psychology\"), attachment theory has implications and practical applications in social policy, decisions about the care and welfare of children and mental health."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the attachment behaviours in infants?",
  "Answer": "Pre-attachment behaviours occur in the first six months of life. During the first phase (the first eight weeks), infants smile, babble, and cry to attract the attention of potential caregivers. Although infants of this age learn to discriminate between caregivers, these behaviours are directed at anyone in the vicinity.\\n\\nDuring the second phase (two to six months), the infant discriminates between familiar and unfamiliar adults, becoming more responsive toward the caregiver; following and clinging are added to the range of behaviours. The infant's behaviour toward the caregiver becomes organized on a goal-directed basis to achieve the conditions that make it feel secure.\\n\\nBy the end of the first year, the infant is able to display a range of attachment behaviours designed to maintain proximity. These manifest as protesting the caregiver's departure, greeting the caregiver's return, clinging when frightened, and following when able.\\n\\nWith the development of locomotion, the infant begins to use the caregiver or caregivers as a \"safe base\" from which to explore. Infant exploration is greater when the caregiver is present because the infant's attachment system is relaxed and it is free to explore. If the caregiver is inaccessible or unresponsive, attachment behaviour is more strongly exhibited. Anxiety, fear, illness, and fatigue will cause a child to increase attachment behaviours.\\n\\nAfter the second year, as the child begins to see the caregiver as an independent person, a more complex and goal-corrected partnership is formed. Children begin to notice others' goals and feelings and plan their actions accordingly."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the principles of attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Modern attachment theory is based on three principles:\\n\\n1.  Bonding is an intrinsic human need.\\n2.  Regulation of emotion and fear to enhance vitality.\\n3.  Promoting adaptiveness and growth."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment related to different cultures?",
  "Answer": "In Western culture child-rearing, there is a focus on single attachment to primarily the mother. This dyadic model is not the only strategy of attachment producing a secure and emotionally adept child. Having a single, dependably responsive and sensitive caregiver (namely the mother) does not guarantee the ultimate success of the child. Results from Israeli, Dutch and east African studies show children with multiple caregivers grow up not only feeling secure but developed \"more enhanced capacities to view the world from multiple perspectives.\" This evidence can be more readily found in hunter-gatherer communities, like those that exist in rural Tanzania.\\n\\nIn hunter-gatherer communities, in the past and present, mothers are the primary caregivers but share the maternal responsibility of ensuring the child's survival with a variety of different [allomothers](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Allomothering). So while the mother is important, she is not the only opportunity for relational attachment a child can make. Several group members (with or without blood relation) contribute to the task of bringing up a child, sharing the parenting role and therefore can be sources of multiple attachments. There is evidence of this communal parenting throughout history that \"would have significant implications for the evolution of multiple attachments.\"\\n\\nIn \"non-metropolis\" India (where \"dual-income nuclear families\" are more the norm and dyadic mother relationship is), where a family normally consists of 3 generations (and if lucky 4: great-grandparents, grandparents, parents, and child or children), the child or children by default have four to six caregivers from whom to select their \"attachment figure\". And a child's \"uncles and aunts\" (father's siblings and their spouses) also contribute to the child's psycho-social enrichment.\\n\\nAlthough it has been debated for years, and there are differences across cultures, research has shown that the three basic aspects of attachment theory are, to some degree, universal. Studies in Israel and Japan resulted in findings that diverge from a number of studies completed in Western Europe and the United States. The prevailing hypotheses are: 1) that secure attachment is the most desirable state, and the most prevalent; 2) maternal sensitivity influences infant attachment patterns; and 3) specific infant attachments predict later social and cognitive competence."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the significance of attachment patterns?",
  "Answer": "There is an extensive body of research demonstrating a significant association between attachment organizations and children's functioning across multiple domains. Early insecure attachment does not necessarily predict difficulties, but it is a liability for the child, particularly if similar parental behaviours continue throughout childhood. Compared to that of securely attached children, the adjustment of insecure children in many spheres of life is not as soundly based, putting their future relationships in jeopardy. Although the link is not fully established by research and there are other influences besides attachment, secure infants are more likely to become socially competent than their insecure peers. Relationships formed with peers influence the acquisition of social skills, intellectual development and the formation of social identity. Classification of children's peer status (popular, neglected or rejected) has been found to predict subsequent adjustment. Insecure children, particularly avoidant children, are especially vulnerable to family risk. Their social and behavioural problems increase or decline with deterioration or improvement in parenting. However, an early secure attachment appears to have a lasting protective function. As with attachment to parental figures, subsequent experiences may alter the course of development.\\n\\nStudies have suggested that infants with a high risk for [autism spectrum disorders](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Autism_spectrum_disorders) (ASD) may express attachment security differently from infants with a low risk for ASD. Behavioural problems and social competence in insecure children increase or decline with deterioration or improvement in the quality of parenting and the degree of risk in the family environment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is securely attached in adults?",
  "Answer": "Securely attached adults have been \"linked to a high need for achievement and a low fear of failure (Elliot & Reis, 2003)\". They will positively approach a task with the goal of mastering it and have an appetite for exploration in achievement settings (Elliot & Reis, 2003). Research shows that securely attached adults have a \"low level of personal distress and high levels of concern for others\". Due to their high rates of [self-efficacy](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Self-efficacy), securely attached adults typically do not hesitate to remove a person having a negative impact on problematic situations they are facing. This calm response is representative of the securely attached adult's emotionally regulated response to threats that many studies have supported in the face of diverse situations. Adult secure attachment comes from an individual's early connection with their caregiver(s), genes and romantic experiences.\\n\\nWithin romantic relationships, a securely attached adult will appear in the following ways: excellent conflict resolution, mentally flexible, effective communicators, avoidance of manipulation, comfortable with closeness without fearfulness of being enmeshed, quickly forgiving, viewing sex and emotional intimacy as one, believing they can positively impact their relationship, and caring for their partner in the way they want to be cared for. In summation, they are great partners who treat their spouses very well, as they are not afraid to give positive and ask for their needs to be met. Securely attached adults believe that there are \"many potential partners that would be responsive to their needs\", and if they come across an individual who is not meeting their needs, they will typically lose interest very quickly. In a study comparing secure-secure and secure-various attachment style relationships, there was no fluctuation in positive relational functioning. However, in any combination of two partners with attachment styles outside of security, the relationships showed high levels of negative relationship functioning. This research indicates that it only takes one securely attached partner within a romantic relationship to maintain healthy, emotional relationship functioning.\\n\\nSexually, securely attached individuals are less likely to be involved in one-night stands or sexual activity outside of the primary relationship, and more likely to report mutual initiation and enjoyment of sex."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-preoccupied in adults?",
  "Answer": "Anxious-preoccupied adults seek high levels of intimacy, approval and responsiveness from partners, becoming overly dependent. They tend to be less trusting, have less positive views about themselves and their partners, and may exhibit high levels of emotional expressiveness, worry and impulsiveness in their relationships. The anxiety that adults feel prevents the establishment of satisfactory defence exclusion. Thus, it is possible that individuals that have been anxiously attached to their attachment figure or figures have not been able to develop sufficient defences against separation anxiety. Because of their lack of preparation these individuals will then overreact to the anticipation of separation or the actual separation from their attachment figure. The anxiety comes from an individual's intense and\/or unstable relationship that leaves the anxious or preoccupied individual relatively defenceless. Adults with this attachment style tend to look way too far into things, whether that's a text message or a face-to-face conversation. Their thoughts and actions can lead to a painful cycle of self-fulfilling prophecies and even self-sabotage. They often seek a dismissive-avoidant partner."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is dismissive-avoidant in adults?",
  "Answer": "Dismissive-avoidant adults desire a high level of independence, often appearing to avoid attachment altogether. They view themselves as self-sufficient, invulnerable to attachment feelings and not needing close relationships. They tend to suppress their feelings, dealing with conflict by distancing themselves from partners of whom they often have a poor opinion. Adults lack the interest in forming close relationships and maintaining emotional closeness with the people around them. They have a great amount of distrust in others but at the same time possess a positive model of self, they would prefer to invest in their own ego skills. Because of their distrust they cannot be convinced that other people have the ability to deliver emotional support. They try to create high levels of self-esteem by investing disproportionately in their abilities or accomplishments. These adults maintain their positive views of self, based on their personal achievements and competence rather than searching for and feeling acceptance from others. These adults will explicitly reject or minimize the importance of emotional attachment and passively avoid relationships when they feel as though they are becoming too close. They strive for self-reliance and independence. When it comes to the opinions of others about themselves, they are very indifferent and are relatively hesitant to positive feedback from their peers. Dismissive avoidance can also be explained as the result of defensive deactivation of the attachment system to avoid potential rejection or genuine disregard for interpersonal closeness.\\n\\nDismissive-avoidant individuals tend to report activities reflecting low psychological intimacy (one-night sex, extra-dyadic sex, sex without love), as well as less enjoyment of physical contact. Research has demonstrated that for both sexes, the insecure-ambivalent attachment was related to the enjoyment of holding and caressing, but not to more clearly sexual behaviours."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is fearful-avoidant in adults?",
  "Answer": "Fearful-avoidant adults have mixed feelings about close relationships, both desiring and feeling uncomfortable with emotional closeness. They tend to mistrust their partners and view themselves as unworthy. Like dismissive-avoidant adults, fearful-avoidant adults tend to seek less intimacy, suppressing their feelings."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the relationships involving people with different attachment styles?",
  "Answer": "Relationally, insecure individuals tend to be partnered with insecure individuals, and secure individuals with secure individuals. Insecure relationships tend to be enduring but less emotionally satisfying compared to the relationship(s) of two securely attached individuals.\\n\\nAttachment styles are activated from the first date onwards and impact relationship dynamics and how a relationship ends. Secure attachment has been shown to allow for better conflict resolution in a relationship and for one's ability to exit an unsatisfying relationship compared to other attachment types. Secure individuals' authentic high self-esteem and positive view of others allow for this as they are confident that they will find another relationship. Secure attachment has also been shown to allow for the successful processing of relational losses (e.g. death, rejection, infidelity, abandonment etc.) The attachment has also been shown to impact caregiving behaviour in relationships (Shaver & Cassidy, 2018)."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How to assess and measure attachment?",
  "Answer": "There are a number of different measures of adult attachment, the most common being self-report questionnaires and coded interviews based on the [Adult Attachment Interview](\/wiki\/Attachment_measures#Adult_Attachment_Interview_.28AAI.29). The various measures were developed primarily as research tools, for different purposes and addressing different domains, for example, romantic relationships, platonic relationships, parental relationships or peer relationships. Some classify an adult's state of mind with respect to attachment and attachment patterns by reference to childhood experiences, while others assess relationship behaviours and security regarding parents and peers."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is adult attachment associated with other traits?",
  "Answer": "Adult attachment styles are related to individual differences in the ways in which adults experience and manage their emotions. Recent meta-analyses link insecure attachment styles to lower emotional intelligence and lower trait mindfulness."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment related to offenses?",
  "Answer": "Since early childhood relationships can influence interpersonal relationships throughout the lifespan, attachment theory has been applied in research into particular crimes, particularly those which tend to occur within close relational ties.\\n\\nDisrupted attachment patterns from childhood have been identified as a risk factor for domestic violence. These disruptions in childhood can prevent the formation of a secure attachment relationship, and in turn, adversely affect a healthy way to deal with stress. In adulthood, a lack of coping mechanisms can result in intense conflict resulting in violent behaviour. Bowlby's theory of functional anger states that children signal to their caregiver that their attachment needs are not being met by the use of angry behaviour. This has been extended to theorize why domestic violence occurs; an adult with consistent experience of insecure attachment may use physical violence to express their attachment needs not being met by their partners. This perception of low support from partners has been identified as a strong predictor of male violence. Other predictors have been named as a perceived deficiency in maternal love in childhood, and low self-esteem. It has also been found that individuals with a dismissive attachment style, often seen in an antisocial\/narcissistic-narcissistic subtype of the offender, tend to be emotionally abusive as well as violent. Individuals in the borderline\/emotionally dependent subtype have traits that originate from insecure attachment in childhood and tend to have high levels of anger.\\n\\nIt has been found that sexual offenders have significantly less secure maternal and paternal attachments compared with non-offenders which suggests that insecure attachments in infancy persist into adulthood. In a recent study, 57% of sexual offenders were found to be of a preoccupied attachment style. There is also evidence that suggests subtypes of sexual crime can have different attachment styles. Dismissive individuals tend to be hostile towards others, and are more likely to offend violently against adult women. By contrast, child abusers are more likely to have preoccupied attachment styles as the tendency to seek approval from others becomes distorted and attachment relationships become sexualized."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Who can form attachment?",
  "Answer": "Although it is usual for the mother to be the primary attachment figure, infants will form attachments to any carer who is sensitive and responsive in social interactions with them."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are different attachment styles during adolescence?",
  "Answer": "Here are the attachment style differences during adolescence:\\n\\n*   Secure adolescents are expected to hold their mothers at a higher rate than all other support figures, including fathers, significant others, and best friends.\\n*   Insecure adolescents identify more strongly with their peers than their parents as their primary attachment figures. Their friends are seen as a significantly strong source of attachment support.\\n*   Dismissing adolescents rate their parents as a less significant source of attachment support and would consider themselves as their primary attachment figure.\\n*   Preoccupied adolescents would rate their parents as their primary source of attachment support and would consider themselves as a much less significant source of attachment support."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are different attachment patterns?",
  "Answer": "There are four attachment patterns: secure attachment, anxious-ambivalent attachment, anxious-avoidant and dismissive-avoidant attachment, and disorganized\/disoriented attachment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is secure attachment?",
  "Answer": "A toddler who is securely attached to his or her parent (or another familiar caregiver) will explore freely while the caregiver is present, typically engages with strangers, is often visibly upset when the caregiver departs and is generally happy to see the caregiver return. The extent of exploration and of distress are affected, however, by the child's temperamental makeup and situational factors as well as by attachment status. A child's attachment is largely influenced by their primary caregiver's sensitivity to their needs. Parents who consistently (or almost always) respond to their child's needs will create securely attached, children. Such children are certain that their parents will be responsive to their needs and communications.\\n\\nSecurely attached children are best able to explore when they have the knowledge of a secure base (their caregiver) to return to in times of need. When assistance is given, this bolsters the sense of security and also, assuming the parent's assistance is helpful, educates the child on how to cope with the same problem in the future. Therefore, secure attachment can be seen as the most adaptive attachment style. According to some psychological researchers, a child becomes securely attached when the parent is available and able to meet the needs of the child in a responsive and appropriate manner. In infancy and early childhood, if parents are caring and attentive towards their children, those children will be more prone to secure attachment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-ambivalent attachment?",
  "Answer": "Anxious-ambivalent attachment is also misnamed as \"resistant attachment\". In general, a child with an anxious-ambivalent pattern of attachment will typically explore little and is often wary of strangers, even when the parent is present. When the caregiver departs, the child is often highly distressed showing behaviours such as crying or screaming. The child is generally ambivalent when the caregiver returns. The anxious-ambivalent strategy is a response to unpredictably responsive caregiving, and the displays of anger or helplessness towards the caregiver on reunion can be regarded as a conditional strategy for maintaining the availability of the caregiver by preemptively taking control of the interaction.\\n\\nResearch done by McCarthy and Taylor (1999) found that children with abusive childhood experiences were more likely to develop ambivalent attachments. The study also found that children with ambivalent attachments were more likely to experience difficulties in maintaining intimate relationships as adults"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-avoidant and dismissive-avoidant attachment?",
  "Answer": "An infant with an anxious-avoidant pattern of attachment will avoid or ignore the caregiver—showing little emotion when the caregiver departs or returns. The infant will not explore very much regardless of who is there. Infants classified as anxious-avoidant represented a puzzle in the early 1970s. They did not exhibit distress on separation, and either ignored the caregiver on their return or showed some tendency to approach together with some tendency to ignore or turn away from the caregiver. Ainsworth and Bell theorized that the apparently unruffled behaviour of the avoidant infants was in fact a mask for distress, a hypothesis later evidenced through studies of the heart rate of avoidant infants.\\n\\nAinsworth's narrative records showed that infants avoided the caregiver in the stressful Strange Situation Procedure when they had a history of experiencing rebuff of attachment behaviour. The infant's needs were frequently not met and the infant had come to believe that communication of emotional needs had no influence on the caregiver.\\n\\nMain proposed that avoidance has two functions for an infant whose caregiver is consistently unresponsive to their needs. Firstly, avoidant behaviour allows the infant to maintain a conditional proximity with the caregiver: close enough to maintain protection, but distant enough to avoid rebuff. Secondly, the cognitive processes organising avoidant behaviour could help direct attention away from the unfulfilled desire for closeness with the caregiver—avoiding a situation in which the child is overwhelmed with emotion (\"disorganized distress\"), and therefore unable to maintain control of themselves and achieve even conditional proximity."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is disorganized\/disoriented attachment?",
  "Answer": "In the Strange Situation, the attachment system is expected to be activated by the departure and return of the caregiver. If the behaviour of the infant does not appear to the observer to be coordinated in a smooth way across episodes to achieve either proximity or some relative proximity with the caregiver, then it is considered 'disorganized' as it indicates a disruption or flooding of the attachment system (e.g. by fear). Infant behaviours in the Strange Situation Protocol coded as disorganized\/disoriented include overt displays of fear; contradictory behaviours or effects occurring simultaneously or sequentially; stereotypic, asymmetric, misdirected or jerky movements; or freezing and apparent dissociation. Lyons-Ruth has urged, however, that it should be more widely \"recognized that 52% of disorganized infants continue to approach the caregiver, seek comfort, and cease their distress without clear ambivalent or avoidant behaviour\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many protocols?",
  "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course that lasts for two weeks."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is SAT?",
  "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method, based on creating an affectional bond with our child, for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects, and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is self-attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method, based on creating an affectional bond with our child, for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects, and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "4"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What goal should I have?",
  "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides us towards growth and self-development in society; e.g. success in an academic, scientific, literary, philosophical, athletic, spiritual, professional, charitable, manufacturing, or commercial field."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Can I have goals like making money?",
  "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self, simply called adult, into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self, simply called our child in these notes: The four stages of SAT are 1- Introduction to attachment theory 2- Connecting with the child 3- Falling in love with the child 4- Developmental training for the child"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 1 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "Stage One: Introduction to SAT**\\n\\nSAT is a technique to enhance mental health.\\n\\nLike any other form of self-improvement method, SAT entails serious effort, patience and perseverance on our behalf.\\n\\nSAT protocols simulate the parent-child relationship, which may at first seem strange.\\n\\nTherefore, we should make ourselves informed by attachment theory in general and the scientific hypotheses of self-attachment technique."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 2 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "**Stage Two: Connecting with the child**\\n\\nWe try to distinguish between our adult, i.e. our thinking and reasoning capacity that is more dominant when we are calm, and our child, i.e. the emotions and affects that become more dominant under stress and crisis.\\n\\nWe do this with protocols that involve looking at the two contrasting childhood photos, referred to for convenience as “happy” and “unhappy” photos. \\n\\nBy looking at these two contrasting photos\/avatars and recalling past events and what we have heard from others about our childhood, we gradually think about our early years to construct a basic psychological portrait of the child and our feelings, affects, and emotional problems with our parents and other significant figures in early childhood."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 3 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "**Stage Three: Falling in love with the child**\\n\\nIn this stage, we establish an imaginative but passionate loving relationship with the child.\\n\\nThis falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity.\\n\\nThroughout history, human beings have created passionate and warm relationships with animate and inanimate objects and concepts and have endowed immense significance to these relationships to use them to regulate their emotions.\\n\\nIn self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals. With emotional maturity, primary narcissism is usually moderated by emotional development, but childhood trauma can cause its perpetuation and even aggravation.\\n\\nSelf-attachment makes use of the existing primary narcissism in human beings, in other words, our intrinsic love of ourselves.\\n\\nThe goal is that by falling in love with the child, we become able to have a new emotional birth and growth that will eventually contain our narcissism.\\n\\nHowever, falling in love with the child is quite different from being in love with one’s self.\\n\\nOur adult falls in love with our child as good parents are in love with their children, and attends to the child lovingly but at the same time contain the anti-social selfishness and unreasonable egoistic expectations of the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 4 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "*Stage Four: Reparenting**\\n\\nOur adults must always remember the vow for the unwavering bond with the child.\\n\\nWe choose a short phrase such as “You are my beloved”.\\n\\nWe repeatedly utter it loudly while we look at the happy and unhappy photos\/avatars; the aim is to become habituated to uttering this phrase.\\n\\nWe recite one or two examples of the happy love songs we selected in Stage Three.\\n\\nWe loudly repeat these songs using our whole body.\\n\\nThe goal is that by memorizing these songs, we will get used to reciting them, and as a result always keep the relationship with the child in mind. \\n\\nHabituation to sing the selected happy love songs is so strengthened in this way that we develop a tendency to spontaneously, unintentionally and effortlessly engage in reciting these songs in all kinds of circumstances.\\n\\nAs we become more habituated to singing these songs, we will be able to engage in reciting them even when we are depressed or anxious.\\n\\nThis will help reduce our pain and remind us of the loving relationship with the child.\\n\\nThese exercises help keep the secretion of serotonin, dopamine and other mood-enhancing neurotransmitters at a high level.\\n\\nThis will lead to more hope, motivation, and energy, and will have a moderating effect on depression and anxiety."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do I need role-play?",
  "Answer": "Our problems with properly managing our emotions are usually rooted in our childhood development. This means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress. In SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child, and through role-playing, they become a parent to their child.  The intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh. The adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a brand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potential and higher goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What if I don't have any goal?",
  "Answer": "If we don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, we try to find it as we practice the protocols."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why can't I feel the improvement?",
  "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols. Non-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood, and then consolidated by repetition in later years. Creation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many protocols?",
  "Answer": "twenty-one"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How long is the course?",
  "Answer": "The complete course takes eight weeks, but it is possible to do a shorter version of the course in two weeks."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How much time?",
  "Answer": "Each day, practice exercises for 10-15 minutes twice a day"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attitude should I have to my child self?",
  "Answer": "One of the principles of self-attachment is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child and their emotional problems. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attitude should I have to my child self?",
  "Answer": "Compassion"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How can we learn compassion?",
  "Answer": "We can find examples and role models of good parents interacting with their children in our family, among friends, in the parks and playgrounds or on the Web: they show affection without spoiling their children, hugging and caressing them at times of stress or even in ordinary circumstances."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "This falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is SAT related to role-playing?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a type of double role-playing game in which the individual plays the role of the child and the adult simultaneously."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is SAT?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a technique to enhance mental health."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "The goal is that by falling in love with the child, we become able to have a new emotional birth and growth that will eventually contain our narcissism. "
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is falling in love with the child the same as being in love with oneself?",
  "Answer": "Falling in love with a child is quite different from being in love with one’s self. Our adult falls in love with our child as good parents are in love with their children, and attend to the child lovingly but at the same time contain the anti-social selfishness and unreasonable egoistic expectations of the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is falling in love with the child the same as being in love with oneself?",
  "Answer": "Falling in love with the child is quite different from being in love with one’s self."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are examples of songs for falling in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "My Heart Will Go On (James Horner), What A Wonderful World (Sam Cooke)."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need attachment of nature?",
  "Answer": "Attachment to nature is an effective way to increase joy and reduce negative emotions."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to speak out loud to the child?",
  "Answer": "The purpose of speaking out loud to the child is to create an emotional bond with them and help in their emotional development, to higher levels of maturity. It is through speaking aloud with the child that we can develop into compassionate, creative, happy individuals and reach our goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to speak out loud to the child?",
  "Answer": "To create an emotional bond with them and help in their emotional development, to higher levels of maturity"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is laughing ridiculing?",
  "Answer": "Laughing at things that we have taken seriously is being playful, and not a sign of disrespect or contempt for anyone including ourselves. Our laughter takes place with compassion and love for the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to laugh?",
  "Answer": "The goal is to come to believe that, unlike in the past, in this game, we can see our problems and issues in a positive light and with a sense of humour and joy."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need continuous laughter?",
  "Answer": "Continuous laughter can be the best antidote to stress"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need laughing exercises?",
  "Answer": "Laughing exercises are like an antidote for depression, because it turns the topic of depression into a cause for whole-hearted laughter."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How can we apply laughing exercises?",
  "Answer": "After repeated practice of the laughing exercises, we can begin to apply it to things that worry us in the present and the future."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do I need to reprocess painful childhood events?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment one initially gains the skills to enhance positive emotions before tackling childhood traumas through revisiting and reprocessing them."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What makes us laugh?",
  "Answer": "**What makes us laugh?**\\n\\n1- Superiority (Plato): We laugh when we see ourselves as superior to someone\\n\\n2- Incongruity theory (Kant): We laugh at hearing a joke when its punchline violates the expectation built earlier in the joke.\\n\\n3- “Life is a tragedy when seen in close-up, but a comedy in long-shot.” (Charlie Chaplin)\\n\\n4- Evolutionary theory: Laughter developed in higher primates as a play signal."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are mental exercises?",
  "Answer": "Reading, playing mental games, learning new things, and meditation can all be considered mental exercises."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the importance behind the house building exercise?",
  "Answer": "Children’s early attachment in their first two years is created in the pre-verbal development when their visual experience is their most important tool for interaction.\\n\\nHouse building was one of the first activities of early humans and the instinct for it can be inferred when children start to play by creating little rooms and places.\\n\\nThe objective of SAT is to empower the individual through their own actions and creativity in building a grand and robust mansion.\\n\\nEvery stage in building the new house reflects the progress made in repairing the inner world and developing a new orientation in life."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why can we view SAT and role-playing as a game?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a type of double role-playing game in which the individual plays the role of the child and the adult simultaneously.\\n\\nDonald Winnicott once said: “The general principle seems to me to be valid that psychotherapy is done in the overlap of the two play areas, that of the patient and that of the therapist. If the therapist cannot play, then he is not suitable for the work. If the patient cannot play, then something needs to be done to enable the patient to become able to play, after which psychotherapy can begin. The reason why playing is essential is that it is in playing that the patient is being creative.”\\n\\nChildren learn what they learn and become creative through playing and laughing.\\n\\nThrough comic role-playing, SAT enables the child to become creative. Our problems with properly managing our emotions are usually rooted in our childhood development.\\n\\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\\n\\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child, and through role-playing, they become a parent to their child.\\n\\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\\n\\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a brand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potential and higher goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Does SAT really work?",
  "Answer": "The foundation for developing secure attachment is a parent’s unconditional and consistent love.\\n\\nAs seen in the workshops three different experiments have had similar results.\\n\\nThe brain activity of the following groups is measured under fMRI: Mothers and young lovers look at the photos of their children and loved ones respectively; similarly, devout protestants pray.\\n\\nThe activated area of the brain in all three groups is the caudate nucleus, which is the reward centre of the neural network.\\n\\nIn all three groups the area of the brain that is de-activated is the frontal cortex, which is related to negative effects and social judgment.\\n\\nIn all these cases love and emotional relations activated the reward centre of the neural system, and led to the secretion of dopamine, resulting in hope, motivation, and energy for interacting with the loved one. SAT will help us reülicate the secure attachment we all need from parents."
 }
]
}